

Patrick M. Dunn

860-921-3424 • patrick@thedunns.org

SUMMARY

Web Developer and bilingual carpenter with international teaching experience. Learned the MERN stack while earning a Full Stack Web Certificate from the University of Connecticut. Studied Spanish and German at Wheaton College (IL), later earning a TEFL Certificate which allowed me to teach English in Mexico for a year. Drive to create and build elegantly structured web applications, applying my love of simple and profound functionality from my building experience to front and back end applications.

LANGUAGES / TECHNOLOGIES

,			-	-
•	ш′	Γ N	/	
•	п	1 11	/ I	

- CSS
- Bootstrap
- BootstrapMongoDB / Mongoose
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Heroku
- MVC Framework
- Node.js

- Git
- mySQL / Sequelize
- ReactJS

Express.js

EDUCATION

UCONN Coding Bootcamp, Hartford, CT (Programming Certificate)	2019 - 2020
International TEFL Academy, Chicago, IL (TEFL Certificate)	2018
Wheaton College, Wheaton, IL (B.S. in Spanish)	2013 - 2016
Study Abroad, Santiago de Querétaro, México	Spring 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance English Teacher

2018 - 2019

Applied TEFL certificate by teaching English in Mexico. Gave private lessons as well as classes in various factories for management teams.

ZN Construction, Canton, CT

2016 - 2018

Journeyman Carpenter specializing in trim and molding. Rapidly given increasing responsibility, including the lead on small projects.

Doot Construction, Torrington, CT

2011 – 2016, 2019 – Present

Apprentice Carpenter with broad responsibilities. Received regular pay increases and additional responsibility.

Hartford Family Medicine

Summer 2015

Assessed and routed patient phone calls, managed provider schedules, and processed patient records in bilingual (Spanish / English) family medical office.



TRAVEL / INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Santiago de Querétaro, Mexico

Taught English for a year in Mexico's historic heartland.

Western Europe Summer 2016

Backpacked through France, Switzerland, and Germany.

Honduras Spring 2015

Team member of initiative that brought running water to two remote mountain villages.

Santiago de Querétaro, Mexico

Lived with a host family for a semester in Mexico's historic heartland.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

ESL class, Valley Community Baptist Church, Avon, CT

2017 - 2019

Spring 2014

2018 - 2019

Volunteer instructor at a weekly ESL (English as a Second Language) class. Led activities emphasizing student engagement and fostering original language creation.

Honduras Project, Wheaton, IL

2014 - 2015

Raised money for potable water systems for two Honduran villages through yard work and donations over the course of the $^{14}-^{15}$ academic year.

Tutoring, Hartford City Mission, Hartford, CT

2011 - 2012

Volunteer tutor during high school for an after-school program in Hartford. Helped elementary-age children with their homework, reading, and recreational activities.

INTERESTS / OTHER SKILLS

- German (A2 level)
- Portuguese (A2 level)
- Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
- Wheaton College Club Soccer Team
- 2014 Chicago Marathon
- CT All-State High School Soccer
- High School Soccer Co-Captain